喂！
Hello!
喂，虾头呀，四姨婆呀！
Hello, is it Ha-tau? I'm Auntie!
什么事？
What's the matter?
你还没醒呀，我迟点再打来
Are you still sleeping? I'll call you later
好！
OK!
喂！
Hello!
又是四姨婆呀！
It's you again, Auntie!
你还没起床，那我再迟点打来
You still didn't get up! Then I call you later
不要了，有什么事你说好了
Oh, no need! Just go on!
是这样的，你表妹最近不大舒服
The problem is that your cousin is not feeling well
要出来看医生，为了免她进进出出的
and will go to see doctor! To avoid wasting time in travelling
所以索性叫她在你那里住两天好不好
I'll let her live with you for several day! OK?
原来我还有表妹吗？
Didn't I have a cousin really?
就是你二舅父的女儿阿娥呀！
She's your second uncle's daughter, Ah-ngor!
是谁呢？
Who is it?
我以为你不在家呢，我是阿娥！
I just thought that you were out! I'm Ah-ngor!
你是不是表哥呀？
You are my cousin, aren't you?
当自己家里一样好了
Just treat yourself at home!
厕所、厨房都在那边
There are kitchen and washroom
喂，有人CaII我，叫他迟些打来给我
Hello! Someone's calling me! Tell him to call me later!
喂！
Hello!
喂，麻烦你叫华哥听电话？
Hello! Can I speak to Brother Wah?
他在睡觉，你那位找他？
He's sleeping. Who is calling?
连我你都不认识
You don't even know me
那你认识他也不会有多久
You must be his new friend
我叫乌蝇，你是谁呀？
I'm Fly! Who are you?
我是他表妹呀！
I am his cousin!
表妹？！随便啦！
Cousin?! Never mind!
你告诉他我正在等肥九出来讲数
Tell him that I'm waiting for bargaining with Fat-karl
你叫他醒了就Call我
Tell him to contact me when he get up
好！
OK!
喂！
Hello!
喂，表妹呀，华哥还没起床吗？
Hello, Cousin! Didn't Brother Wah get up?
还没有，你是不是有要紧事找他？
Didn't still! Is it urgent?
要不要我去叫醒他？
Didn't you want me to wake him up?
不用了，如果他起来了
No, thanks! If he get up,
你告诉他我还在等肥九来讲数
tell him that I'm still waiting for Fat-karl
叫他CaII我啦！
and tell him to call me!
好的！
OK!
眼困就进房去睡吧！
Go to sleep if you are tired!
我今晚睡客厅行啦
I could sleep in the living room tonight!
为什么戴口罩？
Why do you wear a gauze-mask?
费事传染啦！
To avoid infecting other!
什么病呀？
What kind of disease?
医生说可能是月市有事
The doctor said that my lung is malfunctioning
所以叫我出来找个专科看看
and tell me to see a specialist
死不了的，不用害怕
You won't die!
多吃些橙就没事啦！
Just eat more oranges and you'll be alright!
怪怪的！
So strange!
刚才有个叫乌蝇的
A guy called Fly had phoned you
打了几次电话来找你
several time a while ago!
是吗？他说什么？
Really? What did he say?
喂！
Hello!
喂，表妹呀？
Hello, little cousin!
华哥起床了没有？
Haven't Brother Wah get up?
喂！
Hello!
我现在还在肥九那儿收数
I'm still staying with Fat-karl for collecting debt
有没搞错，今早收到现在还没收到
Damn it! You still haven't get the money till now?
明明是玩你，你不要走开，我马上来
He's just making fun of you! You stay there and I come at once!
我今晚没空陪你吃饭
I cannot go for dinner
你自己出去吃吧
with you tonight!
这里有一百元，你拿去吃饭
Here's one hundred dollars for your dinner!
钥匙在地毯底下
The key is under the carpet!
除了它吧，很好看吗？！
Take it off, would you? It isn't looking good
先喝杯茶吧！
Have a cup of tea first!
肥九，我跟你讲
Fat-karl, I tell you...
我乌蝇肯跟你讲这么久
I'm doing you favour to talk with you
算是给足面子你了
for such a long time
我乌蝇的名字不够响
I, Fly, am not famous
不是我不够QuaIi
because I'm not qualified
是我大佬教我做人要深藏不露
also my Big Brother always tell me to be subtle
牛池湾飞机你认识吧？！
Did you know Mr Aeroplane of Agah-chee Wan?!
他在我们场里签了一千六百元的单
He had made a debt of $1600
不过是拖了两天
and just paid it late for two days,
现在飞不起啦，还要坐轮椅呢！
now he cannot fly, and have to sit on a wheel chair
这件事还是我乌蝇亲手做的
I did that with my own hands
你这是抛我啦？！
Are you trying to frighten me?
飞机他算是老几呀？拿他来跟我比
He, Aeroplane, is a nobody and cannot be compared to me
我告诉你呀
I tell you...
我肥九出来混
I, Fat-karl,
向来没有找数这个习惯
never before have the habit of paying debt
别说是你，大圈那个向东够恶了吧？
Let's say that Big-Circle who were more powerful...
现在也变成细圈啦！
and now Big-Circle becomes Small-Circle!
你知道是为了什么？
Do you know why?
就是因为他拿叠单来叫我找数
It was because he forced me to pay his debt,
被我打得他五官不全
so I hit him nearly into death
现在只剩下一只眼啦！
He now get only one eye left!
出来混了才不过两年
Just having two years experience
够胆来向我肥九收数？
don't you have the guts to collect my debt?
我肥九的刀疤多过你的脚毛呀！
I got knife-scars more than the number of your leg's hair!
刀疤？我大哥得一条，你有，我切！
Scar? My Big Brother has one! I'll cut myself if you have!
你切啦！
Cut yourself then!
还没讲完？！
Haven't you finish talking?
还在讲开场白
We're in the beginning still!
讲了几个钟头，还只是讲开场白？
Still in the beginning for so many hours!
你找死呀？！
Don't you want to die?
别动，统统不要动！
Don't move! Everybody don't move!
给不给钱？给不给？！
Would you pay the debt?
给，给，我没说不给！
Yes, yes! Why wouldn't I?
想不到会这么顺利的
It's unbelievable! So easy!
看他的样就知道是鳄鱼头，老衬底啦
I know, just by his face, that he is a sheep wearing tiger's skin
有这么多人在
With so many companions,
要有本事的话，早就动你了
they will strike you in the very beginning if they have guts
你说得对！
You are right!
这个给你！
This is for you!
谢谢大佬！
Thank you, Brother!
大佬，你到那里去？
Where are you going Big Brother?
华哥！
Brother Wah!
你来找Mabel？
Visiting Mabel?
是呀！
Yeah!
她还没上班呢！
She hasn't go for work yet!
我到下面去等她
I'll wait for her downstairs
好呀！
OK!
那间Boutique有好多新货到了
That boutique has a lot of new arrival!
是吗？
Really?
改天跟你一起去看吧！
I'll go to the boutique with you some other day!
好呀！
OK!
Mabel!
来！
Come here!
我还没吃饭，一齐去宵夜吧！
I didn't have my dinner! Would you go eating with me!
不喜欢就算了
That's OK if you don't like to!
为什么这么晚才返工？
Why did you go to work so lately?
我刚刚才出院
I just left from the hospital
刚刚出院？！又去洗胃？！
Just from the hospital? Why? Stomach-washing again?
不是洗胃，是堕胎呀！
Not stomach-washing! It's abortion!
讲笑是吗？
Are you kidding?
你可以当我讲笑
You can treat it as kidding if you like to!
不是吧，有了也不告诉我？
No it won't! Why didn't you tell me that you were pregnant?
你有给机会我跟你讲吗？
Had you gave me a chance to tell me?
我等了你三天，你有没CaII过我？
I had waited for three day! But didn't you call me?
我没有CaII你，你可以CaII我呀！
You could call me if I didn't!
CaII你，跟你讲什么？
Call you! What could I tell you?
告诉你我要去堕胎
Tell you I'm going for abortion
还是叫你跟我结婚？
or tell you to marry me?
认识了你六年，我得到些什么？
We'd been together for six years! What did I get finally?
人，我有等于没有
I felt like not knowing you
钱，就更加不用说了
and didn't even get any money
我霉得连堕胎的钱都要向老妈借呢！
I'm so poor that I had to borrow my mother's money for abortion!
你说，我到底为了什么？
Speak up! What did I do for?
住口！
Shut up!
你从认识我那天开始
Stop saying! Since the day we'd met,
就知道我是个什么人
you knew already what kind of person I am
你想结婚，想赚钱就不要跟着我
Don't stay with me if you want to marry & want money
你别以为一声不响的去堕了胎
Don't think that because you had abortion so secretly
我就会一世都不安乐
that I would feel sorry for all the rest of my life
我不会的！
I won't!
你口里说不会，你的心一定会
Your mouth said you won't but your heart said you will
就因为你不重视我，你不紧张我
Because you didn't bother me, didn't care about me
我就要糟蹋你的孩子
I spoiled your baby
我还要告诉全世界人知道
And I am going to tell everybody
我为了你堕胎
that I had your baby aborted,
等你这一辈子都不安乐
so that you'll feel guilty for the rest of your life
你行，算你行！
You've got the guts!
表哥！
Cousin!
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
表哥！
Cousin!
表哥，有什么事吗？
What's the matter, cousin?
你是不是失恋了？
Are you lovelorned?
你说什么？
What did you say?
你说什么呀？
我告诉你，以后你不要再说这两个字
I tell you! Never talk about lovelorn again
否则的话，我就扔你出去
Or else, I'll throw you out!
你不用去看医生？
Did you see the doctor?
刚刚看完回来
I just returned from the hospital
医生怎么说？
What have the doctor said?
明天才有报告
I will get the report tomorrow!
吃过饭没有？我跟你出去吃吧！
Haven't you have your meal? Go eating with me!
我煮了饭啦！
I have make the meal!
今早乌蝇又打过电话来
Fly had phoned you again this morning
那衰仔有什么话讲呀？
What had the dirty guy said?
没什么，只聊了两句
Nothing special! Just some casual talk!
有没有问我的事呀？
Didn't he ask anything about me?
你什么事？
What kind of thing?
昨晚的事呀
The thing happened last night!
乌蝇只是问了一句
Fly had asked only once!
问一句？问些什么？
What? What did he ask?
我不敢讲！
I'm afraid to tell you!
有什么话你讲好了
Just tell me what you heard!
真的讲呀？！
Do you insist me to tell you?
他问你是不是失恋了
He asked me if you were lovelorned
整天坐在这里，怎么不出去走走？
You have been here for all day! What didn't you go out?
没什么地方好去，九龙我没有朋友
No place to go! I have no friend in Kowloon
快点吃呀，今晚我同你出去走走
Eat quickly! We'll go out together tonight
表妹，你在读书还是做事？
Cousin, are you studying or working?
在做事啦！
I'm working already!
做什么工作？
What kind of job?
在朋友的餐厅里做帮手
I'm working in a friend's restaurant
男朋友呀？
Boy friend?
不算是男朋友
Well! Not quite!
人人都叫他做邓伯
Everybody call him Uncle Tang
等会儿我们去看戏
Let us go to the cinema a while later!
等你有空才说吧，你不一定要陪我的
We'll go if you are free! You have no need to stay with me
班救兵呀？！
Calling rescue?
阿西，输了多少钱？
Ah-site, how much have you lose?
五百元！
Five hundreds!
五百元这么少我才不打
I won't play for so little money!
棺材山地一铺过，一千元，怎么样？
One thousand for one game, agree for not?
一千元，波王，怎么看？
One thousand? What's your opinion, King of snooker?
什么？一千元就想看我的实力
What? To see my quality just by one thousand dollar?
这盘我用单手让你
I play with single-hand in this game,
有种的就赌两千元
for two thousands
单手让我，即刻签约
Single hand! Let's sign contract at once!
阿西！
Ah-site!
单顶！
Single-head!
又入，怎么看呀？
Another ball into pocket! What's your opinion?
是不是，我说波王厉害嘛！
Right, King of snooker is really great!
西呀，看看输了人家几度？
Ah-site, how many scores have I lost?
不用计了，暂时赢你三十度
No need to calculate! He has thirty scores more than you
给你全部入了，都赢你五度
Still has five scores more than you even if you win all the ball rested
怎么看呢？
How do you look?
那就是要SetLOOk架啦！
That means we need a targeting stick!
西呀，拿枝私家Q来
Ah-site, bring me my private cue
开波，开波！
Start, start!
子工西呀！
Stunt Follow
走开呀！
Get away!
Get out of my way!
ScreWBack，现在到SetLOOk架啦
Now, set the targeting stick!
不稳阵，锤稳阵点
Not stable! Make it more stable!
小心点呀，输七度
Beware! You will lost 7 scores!
救波啦，救呀，救呀！
Save that balls! Save it!
你当我死的？！
Are you taking me as a dead!
去你的
Fuck off!
大佬！
Big Brother!
怎么啦？大佬！
What's the matter, Big Brother?
走啦！
Get away!
走呀，去你的
Go away, bastard!
别走！
Don't go!
别走呀！
你妈的，不要阻着！
Bastard, don't block the way!
死呀你！
Damn you!
死呀，死呀！
Damn it! Damn it!
他妈的
Fuck off
大佬！大佬！
Big Brother!
可以走了吗？
Could we leave now?
好了！
It's OK!
静点好不好？
Be quiet, would you?
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
我没事！
I'm alright!
为什么这么晚了还不睡？
Why don't you go to sleep? It's so late
表哥，我的报告出来了
Cousin, my report said that
医生说我没事
my health is alright
我本来想跟你庆祝一下
I want to celebrate with you at first,
不过，四姨婆说这几天
but, Auntie said the weather is fine
天气暖和了，餐厅好忙
& the restaurant is busy these days
邓伯叫我早点回去
Uncle Tang want me to go back earlier
我叫了你两次，不过你都没有反应
I have called you twice, but you have no response
我想你一定很倦了
You must be very tired, I think
热天快到了
Summer is coming
大屿山有很多人进来渡假
& many people will spend their holiday in Lantau Island
不知道你那行有没有假期呢？
Do you have holiday working in such career?
厨房里我煮下了饭
I've made a meal for you in the kitchen
另外我买了几只杯
Besides, I've bought several glasses
我知道，不用多久就全部都会打烂了
I know, they will be all broken sooner or later
所以我藏起了一只
So I've hid one of them
到有一天你需要这只杯的时候
One day when you need this glass,
打个电话给我
give me a phone, and...
我会告诉你藏在什么地方
I'll tell you where it was hidden
拜拜！阿娥！
Goodbye, Ah-ngor!
各位！
Everybody!
小声点呀，小声点呀！
Be quiet! Be quiet!
各位亲友，各位嘉宾
All my relatives and all my guests,
今天就是我弟弟阿西结婚的大好日子
today is the wedding of my brother, Ah-site
酒微菜薄，没什么招呼大家
We've prepared some simple food to serve you
请各位多饮一杯，我先饮为敬！
Would we all raise our glasses I drink first
饮杯！
Cheer!
叫了你礼金不用两百元那么多
I've already said that two hundred dollars were too much
我怎么知道他会在天台摆酒
How would I know he would
那么“缩骨”呢！
hold the ceremony on the roof!
请起筷！
Please eat!
起筷啦，起筷啦！
Use your meal, please!
不要这样，起筷啦！
Don't behave this way! Eat!
看这边！
Look at this way!
多影一张，多影一张
Take one more photograph!
好，好！
OK! OK!
谢谢，谢谢！
Thank you!
快去叫你外父外母出来影相，快点啦
Go bring your mother-in-law and father-in-law to take a photograph!
快点呀！
Hurry up!
阿爸，过去影张相吧！
Father, would you take a photograph!
不影！
No!
影嘛，阿爸！
Take it, father!
不影！
No!
不要这样，去啦，去影嘛！
Don't be like that, go take a photograph!
不影，影鬼影马嘛，影来献世呀！
No! What for? It's really a shame!
要吃你就快点吃
Eat quickly if you want to!
多坐一会儿都会中暑呀！
We must leave soon or else I'll faint
不要这样嘛，老头子！
Don't be like that, father!
没有钱就别学人家摆酒
Don't hold any celebration if you don't have money
在天台摆酒，简直是离谱
Celebrating on the roof is extremely unbelievable
我都不知道要怎样教你
I just don't know how to teach you
你一世人做事有那样是好看的
You have never done a good work in the past
你弟弟，你弟弟结婚
It's your brother's wedding!
你搞得现在这么寒酸？
Why did you made it so shabby?
大哥呀，我不想办得风风光光吗？
Don't you think that I didn't want to make it luxurious?
不过现在没有偏财，你叫我怎么办？
But I have no money! What can I do?
你妈的，这么多说话
Damn it! So noisy!
“屎忽鬼”  ！
Gay fellow!
你说什么？
What did you say?
我说什么？！我说你是“屎忽鬼”呀！
What did I say? I said you are gay!
没有鱼翅你吃吗？没有鲍鱼你吃吗？
I did serve you shark's fin or abalone, didn't you?
就只差些冷气，你这么多说话做什么
It has no air-conditioning! Why are you so talkative?
照我的意思，你只配吃斋鲍鱼
You only deserved vegetal abalone
要不是你女婿说你喜欢吃鲍鱼
If your son-in-law didn't say you love eating abalone,
我会给你吃？！
I won't let you have it!
早知道你这么老土
If I know you are so troublesome,
吃鲍鱼，去吃屎啦你！
I'll give you shit, not abalone!
你这小子想找死是吗？
Are you looking for death?
用东西扔我？！
Don't you dare throwing things to me?
你不要阻着我，让我打死他
Don't block my way! Let me kill him
是不是想打架呀？
Don't you want to fight?
大哥，不要这样呀，大哥！
Don't do that, Big Brother!
想比划一下是吗？
Want to fight, don't you?
喂，你现在想怎么样？走开呀！
Hey, now what do you want? Get away!
我告诉你，你不要出声呀！
I tell you, don't make any noise!
为什么不出声？
What can't I speak?
坐下！
Sit down!
走开呀！
Get lost!
好小子！
Good boy!
坐下，坐下呀！
Sit, sit down!
怎么？不对呀，他是屎忽鬼嘛！
Hey! Is it right? He's really bastard
你是不是要在大哥面前动手？
Do you really want to fight before Big Brother?
是不是呀？
Don't you?
你讲呀，你讲多一次
Speak up! Speak once more!
他怎么样都是阿西的外父
Anyway, he is Ah-site's father-in-law
你这样搞法，即是令你弟弟难做？
If you make trouble, your young brother will be embarrassed
你说对不对？
Do you agree?
好，好，我不对，我错，是我不对！
OK! It's my fault! I'm wrong!
弟弟，今天大哥要你受委屈
My young brother, I make you suffered today
将来大哥赚到了钱，一定替你补数
I'll pay for it when I have money some days
早已知道轮到我们社团的了
I knew that it's our turn
估不到那么快的
But it happens so soon
昨晚警察拘捕了我们二十多人
The cops arrested us last night.
拘捕了那些卒子不紧要
They're just small fry, It's not a big deal
大口基是揸数的
Big-mouth kay controls the money
听里面的人说
They said that
警察正和他谈判，想转他做污点证人
The cops are making a deal with him. They wont him to be turncoat witness
这件事可大可小呀！
This case is quite serious!
所以“阿公”叫我来通知你们
So that Godfather sent me to inform you that,
这阵子没什么事就不要搞那么多事
don't make any trouble if it is not necessarily these days
喂，外面哈林大行动呀！
Hey, the police has a great action outside!
你们这班仆街
All of you bastards
那个身上有毒品、家生呀！
who have drugs and weapons,
快点自己搞定
go hide them away quickly!
华仔，外面有人找你呀！
Ah-wah, someone visiting you outside!
谢谢！
Thank you!
你来做什么？
What are you coming for?
专诚来找你的
I visit you with special reason
你弟弟乌蝇在我们这里欠了条数
Your brother, Fly, owe us a sum of money
几期没还，CaII他，他又不覆机
He hasn't pay the debt for several period and didn't reply our call
我大哥叫我来知会你一声
My big brother sent me to inform you that...
如果明天还不见他露面的话
If he don't show up tomorrow,
就算自己人也没情面给了
we won't give him any chance
你回去告诉TOny，教弟弟我自己会教
Tell Tony that I know how to teach my own man,
至于这笔数，我会问乌蝇的
and, about the debt, I will ask Fly
如果是真的
If it's true,
我明天带他上竹馆去找他
I will bring him to see Tony tomorrow
大哥，找我吗？
Do you want to see me?
你最近很需要钱用吗？
You need money don't you?
什么最近呀，我什么时候也需要钱用
I always need money
不过也惯了，我乌蝇看得很远大的
I'm used to it. I have big prospects
相士说我三十岁行鼻运
The fortune teller told me I'll be freat at the age of 30
到时便一帆风顺，扶摇直上
Every thing is finethen
那还需要在这里过活
No need to stay here
相士有没有说你等不到三十岁
Did he told you that you can't live to 30
没有呀！
No!
我现在收到消息，说你借了TOny钱
I heard that you borrowed money from Tony
Who is Tony?
I don't know him.
你在说什么呀？
What did you say?
英文罗！
English
你明知我不懂英文你和我说英文
You knew that I don't know English
我问你，你是不是在TOny里借了钱
I ask you. Did you borrow money from Tony?
没有呀！
No!
没有？为什么他们那么紧张到处找你
No? Why are they looking for you?
现在他们在对面宵夜
They are eating around the corner
要不要caII他们过来？
Do you want me to tell them you're here?
好呀！
Yes!
眨什么眼呀
Who are you winking to?
到底问人借了多少？多少呀？
How much did you borrow?
少数目吧，不用那么紧张
Just a small sum. Take it easy
少数不是数吗？
Small sum is also money
多少呀？
How much?
一千几百吧，小儿科啦，不用理他
Hundreds bucks. It's not a big deal, leave him alone
一千几百他们那么紧张来找我
But they come to me
你说不说
Tell me
四围到会，一对龙凤厄，你自己计吧
4 meals and a pair of gold bracelets
这里是八千！
Here are eight thousands!
什么？八千？！你这钱一张当两张用呀
What? Eight thousands? Are you using one dollar as two?
他说就这么多
It's so if he said it is!
大数是八千，还有尾数呢？
The principal is eight thousands! What about the rest?
他呀，四期没供
He haven't paid for four instalments
零头不计，就收他一万三千五
Omitting the odd, he still owe us thirteen thousand and five
当自己人才这样收顺的啦
We are giving you benefit because we know you
你去抢吧！
Why don't you go robbing?
你是什么辈份，跟我讲话？
Who do you think you are? Speak to me?
这么喜欢讲话
So fond of talking
光仔，陪他走过一边去讲足三个钟头
Ah-kwong, talk to him for several hours at there!
是！
Yes!
讲你老母！
Fuck off, you son of bitch!
收声，你同我出去！
Shut up! Get out!
出去呀！
Get out!
你这个细佬好命，跟着你
Your brother is lucky in working under you
如果跟第二瓣，怕死了很久啦！
If he is working for other, he have already died!
不要多讲了，我不跟你计这些婆母数
Don't talk anymore I don't want to talk about that
本呢你就先收回
I return you the principal first
至于息呢，他现在真的没有
But he really didn't have money to paid the interest
拖多你两期了
So we have to delay for two instalments more
又要拖多两期？
Two instalments delay?
不是要拖到我死了才烧回给我吧？
Why not return to me after my death?
你不信他，信我呀！
You must trust me even if you don't trust him!
现在我背上了这条数
I'll responsible for this debt
我现在身上没钱
But I have no money now
过两天我亲自拿来给你
I'll give you after two days
一万八千都没有，你怎么做人大佬呀
How can you be a Big Brother if you don't have any money at hand
不如回乡下耕田啦
I think you better go farming!
我以为你有钱才坐在这里同你谈谈
I thought that you had money so I dared to talk with you
做大佬做得像你这么霉…
You are such a poor Big Brother...
是不是真的要呢？
Did you really want it?
怎么？
What's the matter?
什么？你都丧的
What? You are crazy!
你给得出，我收得起呀，细佬！
I have the gut to take it if you have it now
好，我先打个电话
OK! I dial a phone first
你呀，还在这里做什么？
Why are you standing here still?
你大佬叫你同我讲话，怎么你不讲呀
Your boss told you to talk with me, why didn't you speak?
你老爸叫什么名？
What's your father name?
你老妈叫什么名呀？
What's your mother called?
不要玩了，乌蝇！
Stop joking, Fly!
为什么不讲呀？
Why didn't you speak?
你没有爸爸妈妈的吗？
You don't have parents?
你是不是老板呀？
Aren't you the boss?
不要过来呀
Don't come near to me
我现在有困难，想问你借点钱？
I have some problem now, can you lend me some money?
行不行？
Could you?
行！行！
Yes, I could!
行是吗？
Really?
行！行！
Really! No problem!
乌蝇！
Fly!
今天这些钱是我问你老板借的
Now I borrow these money from your boss
要不要就随便你
It's up to you, take it or not!
不过，我同你就没拖没欠了
But, there's no debt between us from now on
我告诉你，将来如果我有好景
I tell you, if I become rich in the future
我一定会还给你的
I will paid back to you
今日你帮着外人
Today, you are wrong in helping outsider
来对付自己人就是你不对
to beat your own people
是不是？
Is it right?
还不快拿钱去还给TOny？！
What are you waiting for? Take the money to Tony!
算无数！
Cancel each other!
这个，是醒你的
This is given you as bonus!
你真行，在我的场里玩花样
You are really something! Playing trick in my place
你更行呢，玩我呢
You are also great! You've make fun of me!
阻多你一阵
Wait a moment
走呀！
Get away!
TOny，我是叫你来看场
Tony, I'm employing you to guard this place,
不是叫你找人来打劫我
instead of inviting robber to rob me
你现在算什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
老板，他是一时冲动
Boss, he is just losing temper!
现在风头火势
The situation is bad now,
你两个还在狗咬狗骨的
but you two still fighting each other
这是当我死的？！
Are you treating me as a dead?
是他不对在先，欠我的钱不还
It's him who done wrong first Borrowed my money
又来我的场找麻烦，还打劫我的老板
causing trouble in my place, and robbing my boss
话到尾都讲不通啦，阿公！
He was wrong in the whole situation, Godfather!
你明知道他丧，就不要去动他
You know he is crazy already, so don't bother him
你也是太离谱了点，这样过兄弟一同戈
And you are doing too much, taking advantage from him
你明知那个场是他看的嘛
You must know that he was guarding that place!
阿公，我都是下爬呀
Godfather, I'm giving back!
如果要还钱的，不是还给他罗
He want the money back, so I paid the debt
我们无数了
We've made an equal exchange!
无数？！
Equal?
你们俩做什么？
What are you doing?
有我在一日就由我揸主意
I'm the one who make decision till I die
这么多事！
So troublesome!
我现在告诉你们，你每个月供还给他
Now I tell you two, you paid the instalments every month
这件事就这样算数，揸爬啦！
And the event is settled in this way Make a vow!
你们两个还做什么？我叫你们妥就妥
What are you two doing? I told you two to make agreement!
还不揸？！揸！
Have a hand-shake? Shake
阿基那个反骨仔现在做了污点证人
Ah-kay, the traitor, is a witness for the police
这个人不可以留着
We cannot let this guy survived
在没上庭之前杀了他
Kill him before he go to court
你们俩怎么看呢？
What's your opinion?
难道这么高，叫那个呢？
The task is difficult! Which one should we send?
这件事我不想找外人做
I don't want outsider to take this case
不如这样
Let's make it this way
你们俩找几个醒目点的靓仔
You two, find some smart boys
过两天执生死筹
to draw dead lots two days later
就他好了，又够胆，又够串
He's the one, brave, and haughty
叫你细佬呀，他肯做的话
Send your younger brother if he wish to do it
我就蚀底点，他欠我的钱不用还
I'll let him go! I'll let him not paying my debt
衰了还有安家费
His family can have subsidize if he fail
够不够姜先？！
Do you have the guts?
什么？你说什么？大我呀？！
What? What did you say? Frightening me?
收声！
Shut up!
不要玩那些兄弟
Don't making fun of the followers
这里最姜的就是你同我
You and me are the bravest
这件事不是你就是我了
It's either you or me to take this case
你不做就我做，你开声就无所谓了
I'll do it if you don't, say it and I'll take it!
不出声就当你做了
You'll do if you don't speak up
你肯认衰仔讲声不做，就我好了
Say you don't and admit that you are a coward. And I'll take the case
省省吧！
Wake up!
现在你两兄弟是夹埋来屈我了？！
Now you two are pushing me together?
好啦，我劈完你们俩再去劈他
OK! I kill you two first and then I'll kill him
又来啦，别吵！
Not again! Stop quarrelling!
这件事怎样做我自然有分数
I have my plan in handling this case
你们先出去！
All of you go out first
走了，阿公！
I leave now, Godfather!
华仔，回来！
Ah-wah, come back!
我知道你同你条“靓”好好感情
I know that you and your brother are good friends
但是他做事太癫啦，多教教他
But he is too crazy. Teach him...
否则就等于放个计时炸弹在身边
or he will like a time-bomb beside you
迟早会害死你的
and some day he will cause you deadly trouble
我知道，我也想过了
I know, I have think of it
我想找个正行他做
I want to find him a job
这就好啦！
It's good to do it!
鱼旦，鱼…
Fishballs...
今天完了，收工
That's all for today
乌蝇哥，华哥来了
Brother fly, brother wah is here
喂！顶住先呀！
Hey, you deal with him
鱼旦，鱼旦呀！…
Fishballs...
喂乌蝇    大哥
Fly Big brother
拿一串来，怎样呀？
Give me one
什么怎样呀
What?
做那一个几毫生意也不行吗？
Do you mean I can't do small business?
我是什么人呀
Do you know who I am?
是罗，慢慢做，迟些越做越发的
You'll develop into big business
是呀，今天我在这里卖鱼旦
Yeah, I sell fishballs here today
迟些我在中东卖飞弹
Someday I'll sell bounbs in Middle East
乱说啦    走鬼呀
Bull shit Police is coming
不要走…
Wait a minute...
喂走鬼呀
Police is coming
走什么鬼
What the hell!
喂鱼旦佬，架车是不是你的？
Does this cart belong to you. Fishball man
你叫谁呀    鱼旦佬罗
What's your name? Fishball man
什么鱼旦佬呀？
What?
不是卖鱼旦
If you don't sell fishballs
拿着剪刀企在这里做什么呀？
You stand here with scissors?
拿着剪刀就是鱼旦佬呀
How come so you're Fishball man
你发鸡盲呀，我剪鼻毛吧
I'm just cutting my vibrissae
不是你吗？搬它走
So it's not your cart. Take it away
搬走吧，无眼看
Take it
喂！你算怎样呀
Hey! What are you doing?
架车仔和鱼旦不用钱买的吗？
The cart and the fishballs are bought by money
钱是小，面子是大
Money doesn't matter. But pride matters
我乌蝇的名字虽然不出名，但有人知
I'm not famous. But people know me
叫我推着架鱼旦车到处走
I don't want to sell fishballs
我还用出来行吗？
I Want to hang around
走开，买了间戏院呀，走开
Get lost, get away
现在叫你去干活，跟出来行没有关系
I want you to have a job
我不喜欢卖鱼旦呀
I don't like selling fishballs
你不卖鱼旦，你喜欢卖什么呀？
What do you like to sell?
文又不行，武也不行
You can't do anything
整天紧着出来行
Just hang around
说了你不是这种材料啦
You are not anything
是，我不是这种材料
Yeah, I'm not anything
我最适合去卖鱼旦
I can only sell fishballs
好，你叫我卖我便去卖罗
You ask me to do that
卖到有一天我受不了
If I can't stand anymore
我放些山埃落去毒死他们吧
I'll put poison on the fishballs
为你好吧，你知不知呀？
It's good for you. Do you understand?
Hi，这么巧呀？
Hi, what a coincident!
对呀，真巧！
Right! Really a coincident!
你好吗？
How are you?
好！…我结婚了
Fine! I have married!
好事，你老公对你怎么样？
Good! Are your husband treating you good?
不错！
Quite good!
这么大的雨，也不知要等到什么时候
So heavy is the rain! Who knows hot long will I have to wait!
我在等我老公来接我
I'm waiting for my husband!
抽不抽烟呀？
Have a cigarette?
我戒了！
I didn't smoke anymore!
不是你的
It's not yours
我走了！
I leave now!
拜拜！
Goodbye!
阿娥在吗？
Is Ah-ngor here?
她不在，是谁找她呀？
She is not here. Who are you?
不用了，谢谢！
It's alright. Thanks
小姐！
Lady!
什么事？
What's the matter?
阿娥在吗？
Is Ah-ngor here?
不清楚，她好像去了九龙还没回来
I'm not sure! She had went to Kowloon and still haven't returned
去了九龙？！
To Kowloon?
是呀！
Yes!
谢谢！
Thank you
不客气！
You're welcome
几时来的？
When did you arrive?
刚刚来的？
I just arrived
你好像肥了些！
You look a bit fatter than before
少少！
A little bit
你也是！
So are you
全靠他，他是我的医生
It's all because of him He's my doctor
你今晚在这里过夜？！
Would you stay up here tonight?
不…我现在要回去了
No... I'm going home now
阿娥
Ah-ngor!
我想告诉你，我找到那只杯啦！
I just wanted to you tell that I've found that glass
张小姐CaII你
Miss Cheung called you just now
她说她现在正赶去梅窝码头
She said that she was going to the pier of Silver-mine Bay
叫你无论如何都要等她
and told you to wait for her anyway
你可以先上去睡觉
You may go to sleep
明天我再帮你Checkin
& I'll check in for you tomorrow
好
OK!
明早几点返工？
When do you go to work next morning?
很早的，我煮早餐你吃好吗？
Very early! I'll make breakfast for you
好
Good!
你打算住多久？
How long will you live in here?
无所谓
It depends!
我先走了
I leave now
我送你
I see you off
不用了，很近呀
That's OK! It's near
你今晚可以不回去吗？
Would you not go home tonight?
为什么到现在才来找我？
Why do you not visit me until now?
因为我自己知道自己的事
Because, I know myself clearly
我不可以答应你些什么
I cannot promise you anything
如果我不是挂着你，我不会进来找你
If I'm not missing you, I won't visit you today
如果你再不来找我
If you don't visit me in these days
我可能同那个医生结婚
I will probably marry that doctor
鱼蛋佬，我要一元，要多点酱
Fish-ball guy, give me one dollar of fish-ball with more dressing
摆呀，怎么不摆？多点酱嘛
Take it, why don't you take it? You've said you want more dressing!
摆呀，不摆我会庆的
Take it or I'll get mad
鱼蛋佬？！你妈的！
Fish-ball guy? Damn you!
不是吧，乌蝇哥，怎么霉成这样？
It won't, Mr Fly! Why are you so poor?
搞到摆鱼蛋档？！
You don't have to sell fish-ball, do you?
阴功罗
Poor guy
一定是你大佬指使你的
It must be your Big Brother who told you to do so
你呀就不要跟他了
You should leave your Big Brother
你看我的马，个个身光颈靓
Look at my followers, all dressed up!
摆大哥电话，用得着做吗？
Taking wireless telephone, do you need that?
你跟的那个大佬
You bastard! Your Big Brother sent you
叫你站在街上卖鱼蛋
selling fish-ball in the street
跟我不是更好
Working for me is better!
走鬼呀！
Escape
走什么走呢？你是古惑仔呀
Escape for what? You are a gangster!
有这么多兄弟在这里，你怕差人？！
We have so crowd of gangsters here! It's no need to afraid!
动他呀！
Beat him!
不用怕，有什么事进去了也不用怕
Don't be afraid! You'll be alright even if you're in jail
有人敢动你马上还手
Fight back at one if someone beat you
不要影衰班兄弟
Don't make us lose faces
你这衰人，你…
You bastard, you...
不用这么紧张，没事的
Take it easy! It's OK!
你又不是卖白粉，只是卖鱼蛋嘛
You are not selling drugs, just fish-ball
看戏！
Something good to be seen
打四万啦！
Beat him!
他妈的，别走呀！
Hey, don't go you bastard
还走？
Don't go!
去死啦！
Go to hell, bastard!
拖他过来！
Take him here
饮完啦！
Finished drinking
对了，两箱鸡翼你猜有多少只？
Right! How many chicken wings are there in two boxes
二、三百只啦！
About two or three hundreds!
二、三百只？！
Two or three hundreds?
喂，你回去了记得告诉你老板
Hey, go back and tell your boss...
以后不要再叫你一个人搬
not to send you to take thing
这么重的东西
so heavy alone
告诉他，一只鸡翼打一捶
Or else, I'll give him one fist for one wing in return
神经病！
You are crazy
我神经病？
I am crazy?
是不是不想我帮你？
Do you want me to help you?
无所谓，反正我都不打算做了
It's OK! Anyway, I will quit!
不做，为什么？
Quit! Why?
我想到九龙去找工做
I want to find a job in Kowloon
好呀，方便我，搬到我家来呀
Good! It's doing me favour! You can live in my house!
你不要讲第二次
Don't say the second time
讲了第二次就收不回了
You can't deny it if you say it twice
我不是讲笑的
I'm not kidding!
我出了去就不会再回来
I go out and will never come back
喂，你吃什么呀？
Hey, what do you want to eat?
你告诉他，我会准时上竹馆找他
Tell him that I'll go to find him on time
如果乌蝇少了一条毛，唯他是问
If Fly has anything wrong, he'll pay for it
就这样啦
It's finished!
什么事呀？
What's the matter?
没什么，我现在要出去，乌蝇出了事
Nothing special! Fly has some problem and I'm going out now
会不会有危险？！
Would it be dangerous?
没事的，我今晚就回来放心
No, it'll be alright, I'll be back tonight
土申叔，这么多人呀？
Uncle Kwan, so many people here?
华仔，这件事是乌蝇不对
Ah-wah, it's Fly doing wrong in this case
不过，大家是自己人，无谓搞大了
But, I don't want to make it big since we all know each other
过去跟TOny讲几句好话吧！
Say something good to Tony & the case will be settled
TOny，乌蝇就算有什么不对
Tony, no matter what did Fly do,
我都会执行家法
I'll punish him according to my rules
请你把我细佬交给我
So please give me back my brother
细佬？！什么细佬呀？
Brother? What kind of brother?
这个是细佬吗？你喜欢掩住你的细佬
Is this a brother? You like to protect your brother
现在掩住他呀
now you are protecting him!
同我玩花样？是好马就该掩住他
Making fun of me? You should protect him if he is good
你掩住“劈”屎，你怎么做人大佬呀
Now you are just protecting a lump of shit How can you be a Big Brother?
TOny，拿回个彩就算了
Tony, stop when you have some advantage
无谓去得这么尽
Don't go too far
坤叔，你省省吧，我是教识他做人
Uncle Kwan, save it for yourself! I'm teaching him to grow up
他的马可以这样对我
His gangster can treat me like this
将来你们还有地方立足吗？
Where can we stand in the future then?
人呢，我一定会做
I'll release him surely!
不过一定要我麻，我的要求好低
But I must be satisfied My requirement is low
只要你讲一句我喜欢听的
Just say one sentence I like
我就速速放人
I'll release him
这句说话你喜不喜欢听？
Do you like to hear these words
你要不要你弟弟？
Do you want your brother?
华仔！
Ah-wah!
大佬！
Big Brother
你好！
Are you alright?
能不能走？
Can you walk?
能！
Yes, I can
你的“靓”扶起他，叫呀！
Tell your follower to help him stand
扶起他！
Help him stand
不用，我自己起来！
No, I can stand by myself
我自己走可以了
I can walk by myself
不要过来
Don't get near to me
大佬！大佬！
Big Brother! Big Brother!
我告诉你们俩
I tell you two,
这件事就算找天皇出来也没得拆
this case can't be settled even if you bring the highest King
乌蝇，这件事情肯定还有下文
Fly, this case certainly won't end up this way
这些钱你拿去
You take this money
回调景岭要等事情淡了些才好出来
And go back to Til-gang Lin and wait for the case to fade out
我不回去！
I won't go!
我发过誓
I've made a vow
我不发达就不回调景岭见我老妈
I won't go back to see my mother if I do not succeed
好，我同你去大屿山
OK, I go to Lantau Island with you
为什么你一定要我走呢？
Why do you drive me away so insistly?
为什么？我不想明天你一出门口
Why? I don't want you to be killed tomorrow
就被人斩开几碌
when you go out
你明知道那只是癫狗
You know he is just a mad dog
为什么你不听我的话，偏要去惹他
Why don't you listen to me not to provoke him?
不是我惹他，是他先来惹我呀
It's him who provoked me, I didn't provoke him
难道我不该玩他，现在我玩他不起吗
Don't you think I should just about it! I have the power to play, haven't I?
你玩得起吗？！
Don't you have the power to play with him?
你玩得起就不会被人打到像个猪头炳
If you have, you won't be beaten so heavily and have face swollen up
是，我是被人打得像猪头炳
Yes, I was beaten to have face swollen
你嫌我映衰你，就别理我好了
You are blaming me on losing you face, you can leave me alone
是你自己说的，不要贪口爽呀
No one force you to speak this Don't speak it for fun
我现在就不理你
I leave you alone now
如果你明天出门口没事的话
If you are safe when you go out tomorrow
我就替你挽鞋
I'll do anything for you
我们一向都不知道明天会怎么样？
We all don't know what will happen tomorrow
对不对？
Do you agree?
去宵夜
Let's go eating out!
走啦
Come along!
打他
Beat him!
乌蝇，我灭你，我灭死你呀！
Fly, I twist your face I twist you to death
这次我还暗算不到你
I can plot against you this time, can't I?
你不要打我大佬呀
Don't beat my Big Brother
和他无关的，要打便打我吧
Leave him alone. Just beat me up
打你，我还打得你不够麻呀
Not enough?
我现在打埋你大佬，待你们相映成趣
Let me beat your brother up. That makes you two pairs
我要你亲眼看着，我怎样玩残你大佬
I want you to see how I fool around your brother
他妈的
Shit
反抗呀
fight back
我TOny这份人是最讲公道的
I, Tony, is very justified
你怎样对我，我就怎样对你了
An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth
你别动呀，你那里是最敏感的
Don't move! It's the most sensitive place of you
你一动，就不知道会射到那里去了
I don't know where will you eject if you move
真行，这次真好彩
Great! I'm lucky this time
跟着不知道会不会这么好彩呢？
Will I still be so lucky next time?
你这么兴奋呀
You are so excited
想一齐玩这个Party呀
Do you want to join our party?
好呀，来玩呀！来呀！
OK! Come join us! Come on!
你千万不要动
You cannot move a little
一动就不知道会射到这个细佬
You will eject on this brother
还是那个细佬
or that if you move
不要衰给人家看，知道吗？
Don't let them look down on you?
如果大佬今天没命走出去
If I cannot escape today
你就回调景岭去
You must go back to Til-gang Lin
不要再出来蒲了，知不知道？
& never go out again
硬汉
Tough guy
不过不知道硬不硬过我这个东西
But whether you are tougher than this thing
硬呀，硬呀…
It's very hard... very hard...
硬是吗…硬是吗…
Very, hard, isn't it... very hard isn't it...
看你这臭鸡
Look at you, bitch!
又玩谢了一件
Another one collapsed
你这衰仔，你赖尿呀
Damn you! You are pissing!
你呀应该替他穿了尿片才出来走嘛
You should wear him a napkin before taking him out
人做大佬，你做大佬
What kind of Big Brother are you?
对了，  “得”低个头
Right! Let your head down
用尿照照自己的衰样
so that you can see your face by the urine
看看怎么会这么失败
And see why you are such a failure
然后陪你的威威大佬回乡下耕田
Then, go back to your motherland and farm with your Big Brother
市区的路，不是你们走的，明不明白
Urban road is not suitable for you? Do you understand?
没事啦，没事
It's alright, alright!
你…去那里？
Where... are you going?
我不配做你细佬
I'm letting you lose face
你就当没我这个细佬
Just treat that you've never know me
我都不会再连累你
From now on I have no business to do with you
由我自生自灭啦
Just leave me alone
表哥
Cousin
开门呀，开门呀
Open the door! Open up!
开门呀
Open the door!
快点开门呀
Hurry up! Open the door!
什么事？
What's the matter?
我表哥跌伤了
My cousin felt to the ground & hurt himself
他没事，先让他休息一会
He's alright. Let him take a rest first
你昨晚去了那里？
Where have you been last night?
我同表哥在一齐
I was staying with cousin
你走的时候帮我锁门
Lock the door when you leave!
如果有什么事CaII我好了
Give me a phone if anything happens
她快过来啦
She's coming
喂，招呼人客呀
Hey, receive guests
不好意思呀
I'm sorry
你们慢慢谈吧
You talk to each other first
在差馆开枪嘛，未必会死人的
Shooting in a police station won't cause death penalty
好彩的就坐三、五、七年
Go to jail for several years
出来就是大人啦
and become a man when you come out!
现在人家叫你银仔
Now people call you boy,
将来就叫你做银哥
and they'll call you "sir" tomorrow
想起朵就靠这镬了，知道吗？
It's a chance to be famous! Understanding?
阿公，我不敢呀
Godfather. I'm afraid!
什么？不敢，抽到签你说不敢？
What? Afraid! You've drew the lots and now you said you afraid
就算我不出声，兄弟们都会劈死你
Every colleague will kill you even if I let you go
不要多说了，走吧
Don't say so much! Keep going!
阿公，我真的不敢呀
Godfather, I'm really afraid
没出息
Chicken-hearted
阿公呀，我有些话要同你讲
Godfather, I've got something to talk to you
$23.5连罐，$30不用找了，多谢
$23.5 with tin. Here is $30. No change. Thanks
阿西
Ah-site
大佬
Brother
啊！做了爸爸真是不同的
You're a different person after you become a fahter
无办法，仔细老婆嫩
I have no choice. I have a young wife and baby
为生活，什么也要做的
I'll do anything for living
是的，这些钱拿去吧，拿着
Take the money
做什么呀
What are you doing?
大佬应允了你的
I promised you
上次委屈了你
I'm sorry for last time
今次找一间又贵又不饱补请亲戚朋友
Please find a luxurious resturant this time
剩下的钱，留给儿子摆满月酒
And the lest of the money is for the celebratim of your son's first month
记住，不要衰给老婆外家看
Remember, don't let your wife's famlty look down on you
争一口气，明白吗？
Do you understand?
那些钱怎样得来的？
How can you get the money?
不要理我，不要理我好不好
It's none of your business
迟些大佬不在，有事便找华哥
I'll not around. Call borther wah if you get in trouble
你跟了我这么久，什么大事也没做过
We didn't do any big thing
我做大佬的很惭愧
I feel ashamed
大佬，你不要这样说
Don't say that, brother
听我说完先
Linsten to me
我知，以前在你心里，可能会小看我
You may despise me in the past
是的，我是值得给人小看的
Yes, I deserve that
但是过两天，你看报纸，看电视
But 2 days later, when you read paper and watch TV
你便知你大佬乌蝇不是莫姜的
You'll realize that I'm not an idiot
我够资格做你大佬有余
I can be your big brother
记得告诉人，你今天有个很劲的大佬
Remember to tell everyone you
记住呀
Remember
这些衣服合身吗？
Do these clothes suit you?
整晚没睡，去休息一下吧
You didn't sleep the whole night! Take a rest!
我睡不着
I can't sleep!
不用担心，是皮外伤，无事的
Don't worry! Just slight injury! It's alright!
今次就说好彩无事，那下次呢？
You're lucky this time, but what about the next time?
我做事从来没想过下次
I've never thought about next time in doing anything
除了一样，就是下次我出香港
Just one thing
我要你跟我一齐出去
I want to be with you next time when I go touring
这句说话我讲了两次，亦不打算收回
I've said this twice I won't take it back
你的意思怎么样？
What are your opinion?
来呀，来呀，过来呀
Come on! Come to me!
华哥呀，大佬昨晚给了我很多钱
Brother Wah! My Big Brother have given me a lot of money last night
叫我再摆一次酒
and told me to hold banquet again
他说过两天后看报纸
And he said I would know
就知道他不是莫姜
he was not coward when I read newspaper two days later,
华哥，你快点出来呀
Brother Wah, would you come out at once
你不理他，就没人理他啦
Nobody will care about him if you don't
我现在出来
I'm coming now
又要出去呀？
Going out again?
没什么，是朋友打电话来
Nothing! Some kind of friend
叫我出去聊聊
called me out to talk a while
对了，等一下我要出梅窝
Right! I'll go to buy some medicine
去买两剂铁打药
in Silver Mine Bay
有没有什么东西要买？
Do you want me to buy anything for you?
我好快就回来啦！
I'll be back soon
仔八
Double eight
张小姐Call你
Miss Cheung called you
说跌打药买不买不要紧
to tell you that medicine was not important
最要紧小心点，早点回来
But took care of yourself and came back earlier
又食糊呀
I win again
给钱，给钱呀
Give me money
上数
Count it later
为什么转了地方也不通知我，TOny哥
Why not tell me you're changed your address, Tony?
起身…
Get up...
你知不知这里打几大呀
Do you know the game rules here?
是不是不招呼我呀
You don't welcome me?
拿些安家费来益我
Give me money
我惊会折堕
I don't want to be screwed up
你呀，你已经堕到尽了
You're been screwed up
日日食长斋，生仔也不会有屁股
Even you feel sorry, your son will have no ass
你说什么呀靓仔
What are you talking?
什么呀    什么呀
What? What?
给他威两天好了
Let him be the boss 2 days
他成世也未威过，他拿了性命来搏的
He never be the boss. He risks his lefe for that
威两天也不能，乌蝇哥是吗？
Just 2 days
来吧
Come on
过七筒
seven tile of cirdes
喂，你知不知规矩的，打过啦
Do you know the rules? Get another tile
八呀
Eight
不好意思，自己喷了出来的
I'm sorry
喂，打麻雀吧！
Come on
不要玩花样呀靓仔
Don't fool me
随便他
Leave him alone
给他做多两天英雄
Let him be a two days hero
真忍得呀，食屎啦你
You're very patient. Goddam you!
你不要以为我真的不敢打你呀
You think I don't dare to beat you?
打我呀笨
Come and beat me
你敢打我
If you beat me
你打我一下，我立即躺在这里
I'll lie down
大口基的事你便要背上身
And you'll get into big-mouth kay's trouble
打我呀…
Come on
去死啦
Goddam you!
他妈的
Shit
过来呀，够胆过来我便射死他
I'll shoot him if you move
射呀，够胆你便开枪
Shoot him if you dare
大我呀，是不是大我呀
Are you threatening me?
射我呀，拉鸡射我呀
Pull the trigger and shoot me
不要开枪呀
Don't shoot
不要呀…
No...
惊呀，惊死了吗？屎忽鬼
Are you scared, Asshole?
射爆你的头
Let me blow off your head
不要…，不要开枪呀乌蝇哥
No..., don't shoot him
我本来想一枪射死他
I wanted to shoot him
但你不配
But you're not worth to be shot
这些钱还给你的，拾吧
These are the money that I owe you. Take it
一定要拾，不拾便没有机会的
You must take it. Or you'll lose your chance
我一枪射死你的，拾吧
Take it. Or I'll shoot you
说声多谢乌蝇哥
Say thank you
多谢，多谢乌蝇哥
Thank you
穿西装打太，拿大哥大电话有用吗？
You're nothing even you wear suits with call phone
跟着这些大佬
Be the man of such brother
食屎啦你
And you'll go to hell
大家出来求财的
We just want to make money
他还钱给我也不要吗？
You mean I shouldn't take the money even he pay me back?
拿去跳舞吧
Take it and go dancing
喂！不是这样对大佬呀
You treat your brother like that
喂，妈，我在士多，你上来好吗？
I'm in grocery, mon. Do you come up?
什么事呀？
What is going on?
没有，我知你怕热
Nothing. I know you don't like feeling hot
买了一部冷气给你
So I buy you a air conditioner
我们下面装了，你留给自己用吧
We're installed it down there. This one just leave in to you
我不上来了，你爸爸在
I don't come up. Your father is here
那个是你老公，不是我爸爸
He's your husband, not my father
你走到几时才安乐呀
When will you calm down and stop escaping?
你出来找我做什么？
Why did you come out to see me?
你不要理我好不好？
Why don't you leave me alone?
我不理你？我不理你那个理你呀？
Who will care for you if I don't?
不要以为做完这件事就好威了
Don't think that you'll be famous after this task
对，你今天做完，个个就会说你够姜
Right, everybody will say you are brave this time when you do that
下个礼拜，还有人知道你是那一个
But no one will remember you next week
但是那又怎么样？
But what become of you then?
再迟点就没有人认识你乌蝇啦
No one will know you later
我也为阿公做了不少事
I've done many things for godfather also
我十四岁，十四岁就拿安家费
I had received money for death when I was fourteen
我威过好多人啦？
I was greater than a lot of people, right?
那又怎么样？现在不也是这个样子
But look at me! I'm just an ordinary man now
你威风，你总算威风过呀
Anyway, you were famous for sometime!
我呢？我怎么样？
But what about me?
没有人看得起我，你就开心啦
No one notice me and you are happy about that
我样样都被人家看小
People look down upon everything of me
他们还说我是你裤档里的一条狗
They even said that I was a dog beneath you ass
你知不知道？
Do you know that?
我乌蝇宁愿做一日英雄
I would rather be three-minute hero
都不想做一世乌蝇
I don't want to be a fly for all my life
你让我一手一脚的做一件事好不好？
Let me finish a great task on my own, would you?
就这一次啦
Just for this time
好，你是不是决定要去？
OK! Did you decide to go?
如果你去我就陪你去
I'll go with you if you want to
要是你被人射到了我都替你补飞
I'll take revenge for you if you are shoot down
你不要对我这么好呀，行不行？
Don't treat me so good, would you?
我还你不起的
I can't pay you back
我不想跟你讲这么多话
I don't want to talk so much with you
只要你说去，我就陪你去
Just say it, and I'll go with you
如果你不去的话，一齐回大屿山
We'll go to Lantau Island if you say no
以后的事，我会搞定
I'll settle anything following
好！好！好！
OK! OK! OK!
我跟你回去
I go back with you
阿财，阿财，你不要看不起人
Ah-choi, Ah-choi
怎么你残成这样？
Don't look down upon other
快点同大佬打招呼了
He used to be great and famous but now he was finished
不要这么独食，分一些给阿财啦
Don't be so stingily! Give something to Ah-cho